<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Web_application_security | Pwntoken - Digital Security Research]]></title>
  <link href="http://pwntoken.github.io/blog/categories/web-application-security/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pwntoken.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-08T00:47:45+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://pwntoken.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Shritam Bhowmick]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[shritam.bhowmick@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enterprise Web Application Security Program]]></title>
    <link href="http://pwntoken.github.io/enterprise-web-application-security-program/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-05T04:56:17+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://pwntoken.github.io/enterprise-web-application-security-program</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2><em>Developing Web Security Program for Enterprise Organizations</em></h2>

<p>A long-awaited idea to less complicate <em>web security program</em> came to me while researching and reading a thesis for CERN/European Organization for Nuclear Research to measure effictiveness and efficiency of web security methodologies &amp; techniques for their web applications via employement of <a href="http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-642-13054-0_2#page-1">EAST - Extensible Agile Security Testing</a> on their test subject web applications and closely monitor old security methodology techniques v/s newer ones by two-times iteration of each of the respective old/new techniques.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I have already laid down the foundation of <a href="http://pwntoken.github.io/web-application-security-testing/">web application security testing</a> in one of my previous post. A web application security program is different actual security testing suite and from actual implementation This is essentially the starting point for information security managers to normalize <strong>web application security programs</strong>, required tools, resources, and other necessary tasks to chalk out the right security program planner for thier organizations at an Enterprise level. To loosely present the overall process here, it&rsquo;s relevant to discuss the essential pointers for any web application security program.</p>

<p><u>Note:</u> A Security test plan is different than that of a security program. A security program must be placed first and then this program decides the security test plans with different test cases according to it&rsquo;s requirements (both <em>business</em> &amp; <em>functional</em>). I have had done the extensive research to liquidify and place the procedure in almost fundamental terms as much as possible and fixated this post to explore <code>web security program</code> rather than elevating it into topic of discussing the <em>security test plan</em>.</p>

<p>Basically, an overall information security plan could be reduced down only if certain program is in place in the enterprise organization. This is done via first questioning if any security planning is required or isn&rsquo;t essential to it&rsquo;s business nature? .. and this question is almost always true in cases for enterprise web applications. I have discussed <a href="http://pwntoken.github.io/web-application-security-testing/"><em>security governance</em></a> in Security Testing as an overall process with <a href="http://pwntoken.github.io/web-application-security-testing/">Application Lifecycle Management (ALM)</a> before and would again like to emphasize on &lsquo;governance&rsquo; since it&rsquo;s management of these processes (security program). A substantial information about this <em>overall security program</em> setup could be demonstrated by top-down and bottom-up approches both in <em>strategic risks</em> and <em>tactical risks</em>. <strong>Strategic risks</strong> are those risks which are assumed to be treated before deployment of software (web applications for an instance) and <strong>Tactical risks</strong> are the risks which are to be treated or handled in tactical ways to mitigate risks.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://i.imgur.com/SK3JMhG.jpg">http://i.imgur.com/SK3JMhG.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>To understand how security program can be set-up, there are three primary concerns and focus area for a professional security governance manager, and these are:</p>

<ol>
<li>Security Planning</li>
<li>Security Execution</li>
<li>Security Post-Execution</li>
</ol>


<p>Let&rsquo;s discuss what happens for all of them to understand how this overall management decision turns to be the greatest leap forward to manage security risks in terms of <a href="http://pwntoken.github.io/economics-of-web-application-security/">monetary security gap impacts</a> and also in terms to provide flexibility is a security program setup.</p>

<h3>Security planning</h3>

<p> A robust security management effort can only be a security-centric approach keeping the development flexibility an additional touch to it. By this, I mean a security plan should not block development efforts at all. Some of these are covered in whitepapers - <a href="http://www.sans.org/reading-room/whitepapers/awareness/facets-information-security-program-1343">&ldquo;The Many Facets of an Information Security Program&rdquo;</a> and <a href="http://www.sans.org/reading-room/whitepapers/leadership/practical-approaches-organizational-information-security-management-33568">&ldquo;Practical Approaches to Organizational Information Security Management&rdquo;</a>. What&rsquo;s important is to realize that <u><strong>security planning</strong> is only a part of the <em>overall security program establishment</em></u> process and must never be treated as end-goal. Things can change at later phases which can then need <em>security plan revision</em> and others might later prove to heavily rely on development plans (in case of web applications).</p>

<p><a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-115/SP800-115.pdf">NIST 800-115</a> mentions <em>security planning</em> to be something that is <u>critical to a security assessment </u> and a phase used to <em>gather information required to exercise execution of security assessments</em>.</p>

<p> <blockquote><p>Planning: Critical to a successful security assessment, the planning phase is used to gather information needed for assessment execution — such as the assets to be assessed, the threats of interest against the assets, and the security controls to be used to mitigate those threats — and to develop the assessment approach.  A security assessment should be treated as any other project, with a project management plan to address goals and objectives, scope, requirements, team roles and responsibilities, limitations, success factors, assumptions, resources, timeline, and deliverables.</p><footer><strong>NIST-800-115</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>What basically <a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-115/SP800-115.pdf">NIST 800-115</a> suggests for <code>security planning</code> are a 6 pointer adherence to it&rsquo;s pointers and they are:</p>

<ol>
<li>To develop a <strong>security assessment policy</strong></li>
<li>.. and then to <strong>prioritize and schedule security assessments</strong></li>
<li>.. and then properly select <strong>technical security testing techniques</strong> and <strong>examination techniques</strong></li>
<li>.. and next to consider the <strong>logistics of the security assessment</strong></li>
<li>.. and finally develop the <strong>security assessment plan</strong></li>
<li>And <strong>address legal considerations</strong> for the overall security assessment plan.</li>
</ol>


<p><u><strong>Overall Summary</strong></u>: The first step is transparent and it includes to establish a policy requirement factor for organizations which will provide necessary directions and will also act as an &lsquo;engine&rsquo; to the organizational security establishment. The second step will make sure business critical assets are prioritized and effort driven attention are given to these systems, servers or components that drive the organization. The third step depends on the second point because proper examination and technical security testing are to be considered to benefit from the security program. The fourth step will deal with all the necessary team set-up, the needed resources, etc for execution of the security plan. The fifth step is the most hated <code>security plan documentation</code> and suggests documenting the security plan for it&rsquo;s organization. This is most professional way to approach any problem and determine a solution for them and I find this is the only pointer which will help many-a-times at later stages. The sixth step might be optional but in large organizations - it might as well be essential to consider the legalities.</p>

<h3>Security execution</h3>

<p>One should know the categories and the risks they pose to the organization during the security execution phase. The risks which are being talked about aren&rsquo;t the risks the assessors will be identifying but the most immediate risks which are generated from the <code>security assessment execution</code> exercise alone. There are various levels of risks associated, but this table will try to break them down for clarity and we shall later see why these categories were associated with risks.</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th> <u><strong>Category</strong></u> </th>
<th> <u><strong>Associated Risk</strong></u> </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> Security Review </td>
<td> Low Risk</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Target Identification and Analysis </td>
<td> Moderate Risk</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Target Vulnerability Validation </td>
<td> High Risk</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p><br></p>

<p>There are generally two types of security assessment techniques and these are:</p>

<ol>
<li>Technical Security Assessment Techniques</li>
<li>Non-Technical Security Assessment Techniques</li>
</ol>


<p>This will differ from organization to organization and the most decision makers (the security governance) will choose how much proportions of these have to be employed to the <em>overall security program</em> and decided in the security plan or rules of engagement (ROE). This will be included in the <code>security plan documentation</code> and methodologies adopted will be followed by the security practitioners.</p>

<p><a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-115/SP800-115.pdf">NIST 800-115</a> covers technical assessment techniques and non-technical assessment techniques are out of scope of it&rsquo;s document. But it goes unsaid that non-technical security assessment techniques must be employed as well dependent on the business nature of the organization. For an example - a bank premisis will require thorough non-technical security assessment technique such as lock-picking and lock hardening, identity system security evaluation, interviewing the people in it&rsquo;s organization, etc. It&rsquo;s all a part of the procedure that is to be followed as per industry nature of that particular organization.</p>

<p>For any <code>technical security assessment techniques</code>, <a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-115/SP800-115.pdf">NIST 800-115</a> identifies three techniques and these are:</p>

<ol>
<li>Review Techniques</li>
<li>Target Identification and Analysis Techniques</li>
<li>Target Vulnerability Validation Techniques</li>
</ol>


<p>One would now soon realize how small is <code>penetration testing</code> and will also realize <code>penetration testing</code> is a minor requirement of the overall security program that is about to follow. To detail each of these techniques will require a book and it isn&rsquo;t something I have had aimed for! But in summary it goes like:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><u><strong>Review Techniques</strong></u> - are examination techniques to measure potential security strength of any system. This is the starting point in the security program execution phase in technical terms. Documentation, logs, rulesets, system configuration and files are reviwed and since they are the starting point and no major technical efforts towards big changes are made during testing these components - they pose a <strong><code>lower risks</code></strong> in the technical assessment.</p></li>
<li><p><u><strong>Target Identification and Analysis Techniques</strong></u> - are active techniques such as port knocking, active ping-sweeps, service identification, vulnearbility scanning, war driving and similar checks to find hints for vulnerabilities. This particular type of technical assessment does impose <strong><code>moderate risks</code></strong> because during their execution, certain systems might halt or entirely cease to operate causing productivity failure at an enterprise level.</p></li>
<li><p><u><strong>Target Vulnerability Validation Techniques</strong></u> - are to prove the actual existence of the vulnerabilities. This is where red teams are allocated in offensive ways to determine exposure of in-depth offensive penetration to defend the organizations best interests and their assets. Penetration testing is one such example. Social Engineering is another - and yes it&rsquo;s technically driven. This type of technical assessment imposes a <strong><code>high risk</code></strong> since availability of systems are totally compromised during the test execution and might lead to complete failure from organization functionality perspective.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>This is how internal technical security test risks are different from the risks which security professionals actually measure. And hence these risks become the part of the problem and requires management.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://i.imgur.com/kJcoNGC.png">http://i.imgur.com/kJcoNGC.png</a>&#8221; title=&#8221;Technical Security Assessment Risks&#8221; ></p>

<p><a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-115/SP800-115.pdf">NIST 800-115</a> mentions that <code>security assessment execution</code> is a phase where the security execution starts and vulnerabilities are identified. Methodologies and techniques which are previously decided on <em>security planning</em> phase are executed at this important phase.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Execution - Primary goals for the execution phase are to identify vulnerabilities and validate them when appropriate. This phase should address activities associated with the intended assessment method and technique. Although specific activities for this phase differ by assessment type, upon completion of this phase assessors will have identified system, network, and organizational process vulnerabilities.</p><footer><strong>NIST-800-115</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><u><em>Note</em></u>: It&rsquo;s evident that more than one methodologies or techniques can be used. Some methodologies to be used here for web application security vulnerability identification can be <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Testing_Guide_v4_Table_of_Contents">OWASP</a>, <a href="https://www.sans.org/critical-security-controls/control/20">SANS Critical Controls</a>, <a href="http://projects.webappsec.org/f/WASC-TC-v2_0.pdf">WASC 26</a> or a combination of these methodologies and techniques suited to the organization (<em>which can be developed in-house</em>).</p>

<p>What basically <a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-115/SP800-115.pdf">NIST 800-115</a> suggests for <code>security execution</code> are a 4 pointer adherence to it&rsquo;s pointers and they are:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Coordination</strong></p></li>
<li><p>.. and then <strong>Assessing</strong> the challenges in the entire security framework.</p></li>
<li><p>.. and then <strong>Analysis</strong> which is to segregate false positives, catergorize vulnerabilities and identify the <em>root causes of vulnerabilities</em> (threat trees or attack trees).</p></li>
<li><p>Finally <strong>Data Handling</strong>.</p></li>
</ol>


<p><u><strong>Overall Summary</strong></u>: The first step involves <em>Coordination</em> whereby <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point_of_contact">SPOC</a>  to 3rd party security providers (such as penetration testing, source code review, etc.)  and inter-communication of internal team set-up documented in the <em>Security planning documentation</em> are followed by the key people. Next, <em>Assessing</em> which are provided in the <code>security planning documentation</code> or ROE. These include specific assessors and challenges that come internally to them such as some developers might just harden the systems while security assessments are done due to compliances but forget to keep them upgraded. Next is <em>Analysis</em>, some of which are - <em>Vulnerability Classification</em> which can be done in accordance to methodolgy adopted and planned in <code>security planning documentation</code> (<a href="https://owasp.org/index.php/Vulnerability_Classification_Mappings">OWASP Top 10</a>, <a href="http://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-53r4.pdf">NIST SP 800-53</a>, <a href="http://projects.webappsec.org/f/WASC-TC-v2_0.pdf">WASC 26</a>). For vulnerability meterics - <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Risk_Rating_Methodology">OWASP Risk Rating</a> for Web Applications, <a href="https://www.first.org/cvss/v2/guide">CVSSv2</a> for Network Vulnerabilities (<a href="https://www.first.org/cvss/specification-document">CVSSv3</a> is around too!), <a href="https://cve.mitre.org/cve/">CVE</a>, <a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/">CWE</a> for Software. Security Metrics will depend upon contextx, it&rsquo;s environment and architecture dependent. To create own in-house security metrics, the paper <a href="http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1566509">&ldquo;Security Metrics for Software Systems&rdquo;</a> might just help. <em>Analysis</em> can both be during security assessment and post-security assessments. The last step will inlcude <em>Data Handling</em> - This phase includes collection and handling security data - it&rsquo;s transmission, protection, storage and destruction.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Application Security Testing]]></title>
    <link href="http://pwntoken.github.io/web-application-security-testing/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-26T06:16:19+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://pwntoken.github.io/web-application-security-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2><em>.. is it that hard to integrate security into SDLC?</em></h2>

<p>Web Applications (Useful Applications which can be served in Web 2.0/3.0) today are rich and serve an intended purpose - be it to serve an ecommerce website or host a collaborative API to re-create <em>something useful</em> using <em>new ideas</em> for people and by the people. It&rsquo;s completely safe to assume web applications should have a generic SDLC (<em>software decelopment life cycle</em> or <em>system development life cycle</em>) compared to that of software (<em>as in thick client</em>) and not surprisingly - they do!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Software go through <em>phases of development</em> which is known as the <strong><code>SDLC</code></strong> and represents how a particular task is carried out periodically and efficiently for better code productivity in terms of functionality. A generic overview process of a SDLC is to break tasks into pieces so that they can me managed well and later integrated into a complete working <em>product</em> which can be <em>used</em> for the intended consumers of that product. Similarily Enterprise Web Applications go through <em>application development processess</em> and on each of these phases of the entire process, seperate developers working on an unit is responsible for that particular code and hence is the <em>code maintainer</em>. <code>SDLC</code> isn&rsquo;t short and static at Enterprise level but get&rsquo;s worse and complex when phases begin to shift from one stage to another. There are main ingredients such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>Functional Project Management</li>
<li>Technical Project Management</li>
<li>Information Security Assurances</li>
<li>System Integration Test Plan/Integration Test Cases</li>
<li>User Acceptance Test Plan/ Acceptance Test Cases</li>
</ul>


<p>.. and most of what everyone else knows and what project managers are theoritically trained to prepare for boils down to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Planning</li>
<li>Requirement Analysis</li>
<li>Design</li>
<li>Development</li>
<li>System Integration</li>
<li>User Acceptance and Parallel Testing</li>
<li>Implementation</li>
<li>Operations and Maintainence</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://i.imgur.com/Rxw9UPI.jpg">http://i.imgur.com/Rxw9UPI.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>All of the aforementioned are packaged into the five super&rsquo;s i.e. functional project management, technical project management, information security assurances, system integration test plan and integration test cases and user acceptance test plan and acceptance test cases. We are more worried about <strong>Information Security Assurances</strong> and not long far in this way - we&rsquo;ll be introduced to how <em>information security</em> is governed and where SDLC is outruled by it&rsquo;s superset, and when precisely <em>*security</em> is to be placed into <code>SDLC</code> thoughfully by it&rsquo;s governing superset.</p>

<h2>But the Question Remains ..</h2>

<p><u>How Enterprise Web Application SDLC are any different from Software Product Based SDLC?</u> and <u>how shall security governance take place during the entire lifecycle?</u> Enter <code>ALM - Application Lifecycle Management</code>. To cut short of everything else and <del>leave details</del> to it&rsquo;s own research place:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Enterprise Web Applications <em>differ</em> in production, business case, and it&rsquo;s relative uses than that of a product applications. To elaborate - web applications might die fast due to it&rsquo;s trend nature, user acceptance or short life use case - <em>which means as long as the trend survives, the web application survives</em>, product software whilst might have <em>core re-use functionality</em> in operating systems (e.g. Microsoft Word? OpenOffice? ..). People leave Orkut to go newly obtained trend of Google+ and might never get sick of <code>#hashtags</code> at Facebook but they never leave <em>productivity software suite</em> installed in their PC/Laptop for <em>general core functionality</em> use.</p></li>
<li><p>To take care governance for both - Web Application Security as well as Software Security or for that matter all the five super ingredients we talked about earlier - we have <code>ALM</code> and it&rsquo;s really <em>not equal to</em> <code>SDLC</code>. <code>ALM</code> could be considered as the top gem mounted  above the <code>SDLC</code>, where <code>SDLC</code> lies in the bottom looking up at the <code>ALM</code> to manage it&rsquo;s <code>governance</code>, <code>development</code> and <code>operations</code>. The <code>ALM</code> has control of the <code>SDLC</code> - and <code>SDLC</code> has control of the <code>modular software/application deployment</code>.</p></li>
</ol>


<h2>Shritam! don&rsquo;t tl;dr ALM ..</h2>

<p>.. and so I won&rsquo;t. <code>ALM</code> as you now know is <code>Application Lifecycle Management</code>, it&rsquo;s easier to think of it as a <em>superset</em> of <code>SDLC</code>. If <code>SDLC</code> takes care of the operational part, the <code>ALM</code> takes care of it&rsquo;s governance. It&rsquo;s important to understand that <code>security</code> from it&rsquo;s very core has to be <em>governed</em> and <em>regulated</em> in authoritive perspective or code maintainers would continue to write bad code - and <strong>this</strong> exactly is <em>what happens to the most applications - be them web application or applications/products in general!</em></p>

<p>The three aspects of <code>ALM</code> is to provide:</p>

<ol>
<li>Governance</li>
<li>Development</li>
<li>Operations</li>
</ol>


<p>And all of these three factors are essential to run the show for <code>SDLC</code>, and ofcourse <code>SDLC</code> sometimes depend on it <em>operationally</em> if not for entire <em>development</em> (ever wonder about <code>DevOps</code>?). This is exactly where <em>security professionals</em> should be looking at! If one looks deeper thoughfully, any development criteria is only fullfilled by authorized operational means and if <em>operationally</em> security is placed forward - the <em>secure development</em> will become mandatory. There is a reason why I introduced <code>ALM</code> here because in layman terms:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>If project managers care not to outrule their developers to enforce security internally and make it mandatory, someone else have had got the system processes broken already!</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>Shritam Bhowmick</strong> <cite>His Information Security Diaries.</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Back to <code>ALM</code> basics, what we have is a raw idea which has a potential to either become an end-product for it&rsquo;s consumers and accepted by the massess in core functionality or it dies out and serves a short span of life to benefit from short-term use case/business case.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s13.postimg.org/blw9dfkrr/ALM_1.png">http://s13.postimg.org/blw9dfkrr/ALM_1.png</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>If the <code>security problem</code> at <em>operation level</em> has been identified, let&rsquo;s not forget to take a submarine-dive to explore what&rsquo;s beneath <code>ALM</code>.</p>

<h3><strong>Governance</strong> for ALM</h3>

<p>Take a <em>sweet note</em> - authorities always have a higher ground and what they only know is business, be it short termed or long termed - as long as it&rsquo;s beneficiaries are transparent, people will invest into the project. In <code>ALM</code>, to escalate ideas into businesses, there has to be a purpose; An application has to serve a purpose and then it should have a business value - this is the <code>business use case</code>. Everything else is High-Lower authority for the entire project and they are <code>project portfolio management</code> and <code>application portfolio management</code>.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s1.postimg.org/7hmdr1nbj/ALM_Governance.png">http://s1.postimg.org/7hmdr1nbj/ALM_Governance.png</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>What they do specifically as part of the governance are simplified here.</p>

<p><strong>Business Case Development</strong>: Business Authorities hold the investment share, they have the equities, they know the business, they have stolen the idea ( .. or have them originally perceived!?) and now they are ready to invest on this BIG-O-BANG idea and wish not to lose out on the competitor game. They decide the finances. This first serious move is known to be <code>Business Case Development</code> or <code>BCD</code>.</p>

<p>To support the idea, there are peers who do the analysis for them (business authorities) and chalk out business use for the idea and if they are beneficial to the investors. If they are, business case is approved and application development might now proceed.</p>

<p><strong>Project Portfolio Management</strong>: The people who might have originally perceived the idea, might not have his/her own abilities to implement and transform it into a working product. They need someone else to do it for them and hence <code>people</code>, <code>processes</code> and <code>product</code> become the essentials for any organization.</p>

<p>There are two ways <code>Project Portfolio Management</code> or <code>PPM</code> is carried away - either a <code>project manager</code> is assigned the task with relative technical abilities to regulate a group of people who become the <code>core team</code> of that particular project or there is a dedicated <code>PMO</code> (Project Management Office) to regulate procedures at this level. Here actual development begins.</p>

<p><strong>Application Portfolio Management</strong>: If Application deployment is over, it&rsquo;s now an <code>asset</code> to the organization and more importantly the investors who have invested money into the project. There needs to be an ongoing check on it&rsquo;s beneficiaries and costs plus measures to check if the trend isn&rsquo;t dying and flipping out of it&rsquo;s way.</p>

<p><code>APM</code> or Application Portfolio Management provides a gateway to manage ongoing operation products, provide regulations around major revision (application or end-product software, as the case may be!) changes and perform updates keeping it&rsquo;s <code>business use case</code> in track and perform regular checks on it. If the trend persists, and the end-product or the application is feasibly performing well, updates for better performance, or added functionality is rolled out or a major updates are issued and released. This again needs checks from both <code>PMO</code> (or <code>PPM</code>) and <code>BCD</code>.</p>

<p>Now if we look down here, pretty much during the whole process of life start to life end of the application development or software application end-product development - the <code>governance</code> is constant and does not die out; and this also includes SDLC&rsquo;s in-between (during which the <code>governance</code> hasn&rsquo;t died out either! and as described SDLC is only a part of the entire process).</p>

<h3><strong>Development</strong> for ALM</h3>

<p>Yet again, take a <em>sweet note</em> here - it&rsquo;s not always feasible or necessary for an organization to stick to traditional SDLC i.e. <code>RAD</code>, <code>Waterfall</code>, etc. <code>Iterative</code> might be sometimes the need of the time and more modern organizations have been using them.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s16.postimg.org/8ndjypyx1/ALM_Development.png">http://s16.postimg.org/8ndjypyx1/ALM_Development.png</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>Development is a fundamental necessity for any <code>custom web application</code>, an <code>Enterprise Product</code> or any <code>End Product</code> and this is precisely the <code>security gone wrong</code> point which has <code>SDLC</code> phases in it. During the entire ALM, the <code>SDLC</code> is a part of the lifecycle and it&rsquo;s this point where <code>security professionals</code> should target and permanently set a reminder for a <code>security cross check</code>.</p>

<p>Now, as talked before - generic <code>SDLC</code> has <strong>seven phases</strong> and equally there are <strong>seven security solutions</strong> to neutralize <code>security risks</code> specifically at those places.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s16.postimg.org/akevh1eyt/SDLC_3_Security.jpg">http://s16.postimg.org/akevh1eyt/SDLC_3_Security.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>As to keep <code>security point-of-view</code> in reminder, here are the clauses for these <strong><u>specific security solutions at specific phases of a SDLC</u></strong>:</p>

<ol>
<li>Code Review</li>
<li>Risk Analysis</li>
<li>Penetration Testing</li>
<li>Risk-Based Security Tests</li>
<li>Abuse Cases</li>
<li>Security Requirements</li>
<li>Security Operations</li>
</ol>


<p><code>Security Operations</code> will be talked about when we discuss on <code>Operations</code> segment of <code>ALM</code> where it&rsquo;s an integral ongoing security process. Based on what we have covered so far, we have <code>code review</code> which is to be placed during <em>developing code (development)</em> and this can have:</p>

<ul>
<li>static code analysis and review</li>
<li>dynamic code analysis and reviw</li>
</ul>


<p>.. and then there is <code>Risk Analysis</code> which is covered both during <em>requirements/use case planning</em> and <em>architectural design</em>. <code>Penetration Testing</code> is to be done both and as part of <code>testing</code> and <code>maintainence/feedback from the field</code> which if elaborated falls under the following types of tests:</p>

<ul>
<li>black-box penetration testing</li>
<li>white-box penetration testing</li>
<li>grey-box penetration testing</li>
<li>glass-box penetration testing</li>
</ul>


<p>To really define these and cross the margin more:</p>

<p>A <code>black-box penetration test</code> means there are no external or internal informational put upfront and security professionals should identify and abuse security loopholes externally and if required <em>offensively</em> go indepth of the flaw which means <em>exploiting</em> necessary security flaws to it&rsquo;s deepest extent.</p>

<p>A <code>white-box penetration test</code> means there would be full feedback from the developers or <code>ALM</code> project managers to pin-point <em>resources of interest</em> and if required additionally provide <em>access credentials</em> to <em>security test</em> restricted zones. This sometimes is the industry de-facto because it&rsquo;s efficient.</p>

<p>A <code>grey-box penetration test</code> means to provide necessary <em>resources of interests</em> while the penetration testers are encouraged to find security flaws on their own but not limiting them to be short of credential request, if necessity be!</p>

<p>A <code>glass-box penetration test</code> is new modular penetration test where <code>security test monitoring</code> are placed (often times automated) and people monitor the activities of penetration testers while penetration testers are performing the test.</p>

<p><code>Risk Based Security Test</code> is a suite of <em>Security testing</em> for <em>test plans</em> that are prepared which has to be formulated into the <em>development code</em>, the code is at <em>staging</em> area and isn&rsquo;t gone <em>productional</em> yet. <em>Abuse Cases</em> is where testers pre-discuss how a certain business model could be abused and in what ways it could be defended providing the right solutions in very early phases of the <code>SDLC</code> which is <em>Requirements Planning and Use Cases Development</em>. <code>Security Requirements</code> as fit as per the necessary feedbacks from <code>abuse cases</code> and also performed for <em>Requirements Planning and Use Cases Development</em> phase.</p>

<p>Now if the <strong>Mammoth Security Gap Problem</strong> has been accessed right and the equation is to solve this <strong>security gap</strong>, <code>SDLC</code> is specifically where <em>security professionals</em> should start looking at and because this now has been <strong>scientifically proven</strong> and <strong>deduced</strong> out!</p>

<p>Back to <code>ALM</code>, the part of lifecycle which we discussed have <code>SDLC</code> and this is where <strong>Security gap</strong> exists. There is another part of the problem which has to be ruled out and i.e <code>Maintainence</code>. As <em>developers</em> begin to write <em>code</em> and business case demands more functionalities, more <em>code</em> is generated using frameworks and these in turn have adverse effects ranging from <em>introduction of vulnerabilities</em> from frameworks itself. <code>Code Maintainence</code> have two popular entities:</p>

<ol>
<li>Updates</li>
<li>Patches</li>
</ol>


<p>.. and both of them could do either of the following:</p>

<ol>
<li>either break functionality and feasibility</li>
<li>or break security without letting anyone know</li>
</ol>


<p>.. and both of the aforementioned isn&rsquo;t preferred. This is exactly where <code>ALM</code> has another level i.e. <code>Operations</code> where for specifically <code>security</code> concerns, an organization should have a <code>security operations center</code> to identify vulnerabilities and threat them.</p>

<h3><strong>Operations</strong> for ALM</h3>

<p>No more <em>sweet notes</em>, it&rsquo;s tl;dr: <code>DevOps</code>.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s1.postimg.org/qjakg2b0v/ALM_Operations.png">http://s1.postimg.org/qjakg2b0v/ALM_Operations.png</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>Soon after applications are deployed from <code>staging</code> to <code>production</code>, they start receiving <code>patches</code> and <code>updates</code>. To cope up with these the application has to be managed throughout it&rsquo;s entire lifecycle and is now bond with the developers and the development team. The people who take care basically of both are <code>DevOps</code> and a <code>security operations center</code> here should be excactly placed here to do a routine check of <code>patches</code> and <code>updates</code> and release <code>security fixes</code> for <code>updates</code>, <code>patches</code> or <code>deployment code</code> as well.</p>

<p>And in this way <code>security management</code> is closely packed with <code>SDLC</code> and <code>SDLC</code> is pushed forward keeping <strong>security as a process and not as a product</strong>. This should be the case but ..</p>

<h2>is <em>security testing</em> an intergal part of most organizations?</h2>

<p>And Now we have been asking the <em>right question</em>.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s4.postimg.org/bbuqihcel/SDLC_2.jpg">http://s4.postimg.org/bbuqihcel/SDLC_2.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Economics of Web Application Security]]></title>
    <link href="http://pwntoken.github.io/economics-of-web-application-security/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-22T01:24:47+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://pwntoken.github.io/economics-of-web-application-security</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2><em>and the following isn&rsquo;t discouraging!</em></h2>

<p>Here&rsquo;s why software security would always be a growing concern for leading technologies as well as for them who depend on these technologies e.g. corporations, companies, industry, small scale businesses and at a personal level social sites too. What we are talking here isn&rsquo;t related to a set of standard de-facto technology but what we <strong>are</strong> talking about is the <strong> <em>economics</em> </strong> of related web application software, their technologies and how they can be measured in order to provide a continious flow of quality in security.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Almost everytime a new standard, or a technology is released - it <em>does</em> contain <em>vulnerabilities</em>. Most often, these vulnerabilities are either hunted down using platforms such as <em>bug bounty</em> or otherwise dealt with privately via internal security team or traded in terms of a <em>0day</em>. It&rsquo;s no more about <em>how</em> one was able to compromise the applications in order to gain/trade or protect data but <em>how</em> it could had or has been important to make <em>an impact</em> to the business in concern. Almost all technical security researchers can deal with <em>identifying vulnerabilities</em> and claim they had been protecting the industry - but how about <em>measuring</em> these vulnerabilities in terms of <u><em>monetary impact to the business concerned?</em> </u>  This post is to talk about <em>that corner</em> of web application security industry which hasn&rsquo;t been much appretiated but still remains the core foundation to providing <strong>real security</strong>.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s14.postimg.org/5u25o02td/solution.jpg">http://s14.postimg.org/5u25o02td/solution.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>To <strong> <em>quantify</em> </strong> the expenditure spent due to  the presence of a vulnerability or a chain of vulnerabilities isn&rsquo;t an unknown art - but it is percieved to be as the most analytical security research art and therefore requires patience and core understanding about the vulnerability - most importantly <em>business wise in terms of quantifying them in monetary impact</em> and also in terms of <em>technical impact which could lead to furthur compromise or weaken a particular asset</em>. To me there are three categories of businesses:</p>

<ul>
<li>Industrial scale business</li>
<li>Retail scale business</li>
<li>Personal scale business</li>
</ul>


<p>To each having it&rsquo;s own valuation in the market and having said that I furthur look at asset classifications for them; which is for an example a stock market would be an industrial scale business and they might have these assets:</p>

<ol>
<li>people</li>
<li>investors</li>
<li>investments</li>
</ol>


<p>Now, taking the same example, it&rsquo;s self-evident that <em>people</em> lead to <em>processes</em> in their business as per their role; this could be:</p>

<ul>
<li>HR role</li>
<li>Employee role</li>
<li>Adminstration role</li>
</ul>


<p>Furthur categorization of the targeted asset value will lead to realization that most targeted attacks should be (<em>atleast in my personal opinion</em>) Employee role and Administration role since they the people who have the keys to the technical foundation and now that it&rsquo;s realized that these keys will lead to the door which weren&rsquo;t meant to be open - it&rsquo;s <em>seldom</em> that the <em>people in the processess</em> such as this, become the victim of attacks. At one hand, these people have the keys that lead to <em>secure access/trusted access to data</em> and then at the other hand these are the same people who are least trained to handle a security operation or not trained enough for security policies (<em>even if security policies are enforced</em>). A realistic example here could be <a href="http://www.tripwire.com/state-of-security/incident-detection/dhs-confirms-u-s-public-utilitys-control-system-was-hacked/">compromise of U.S. PUCS SCADA</a>.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s8.postimg.org/hlt0gqp79/statistics_vuln_industry.jpg">http://s8.postimg.org/hlt0gqp79/statistics_vuln_industry.jpg</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>Now let&rsquo;s take for an example a <em>Retail scale business</em> which by far can be any from a cyber security company to a ecommerce based company, a a ventured start-up or a well established commercial platform. These businesses run on <em>consumers</em> that they rely on and hence the most likely target will be <em>consumers</em> and their data. Ofcourse there are other assets such as <em>employees</em> - <em>IT Department employees specifically</em>. Categorization of asset once again will lead to an evaluation of what audience target should most likely be! A realistic example here could be <a href="http://www.techworld.com/news/e-commerce/e-bay-magento-e-commerce-platform-hacked-by-credit-card-fraudsters-3617851/">the breach of E-bay leading to credit card information exposed</a>.</p>

<p>For the third example - <em>personal scale industries</em>, there&rsquo;s social network which people rely on, small scale businesses which are growing but are striggling hard. Most targeted asset should be a single person who holds the data of value. Once this particular asset is compromised, the industry is compromised as well too. This isn&rsquo;t only about the personal industry but by compromising an entire range of information also leads to affect lives of others. A more realistic scenario could be a breach where <a href="http://edition.cnn.com/2015/08/20/us/josh-duggar-ashley-madison/">Asley Madison&rsquo;s site was compromised</a> or see <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/ashley-madison-hack-psychological-fallout_55d4afcee4b07addcb44f5d4?kvcommref=mostpopular&amp;ncid=fcbklnkushpmg00000063&amp;section=india&amp;adsSiteOverride=in">Psychological Impact of a Sensitive Hack</a> - the one which lead to confusions with so many relationships and sometimes when it takes a techical breach to cause a havoc.</p>

<p>Out there is a <strong>huge</strong> economy of relatively <em>economic impact vulnerabilities</em> which are sadly either neglected or often too underestimated in evaluation and therefore <strong> <em>security testing</em> </strong> becomes a repetative failure. What could be a more wonder that a <a href="http://www.csoonline.com/article/2943968/data-breach/hacking-team-hacked-attackers-claim-400gb-in-dumped-data.html">hacking team, the one responsible to hold security for others landing up hacked themselves</a>?</p>

<p>Hence the study of <em>economics of web application security</em> or for that matter <em>information security</em>/<em>network security</em> or <em>application security</em> in general is <strong>that</strong> (emphasized!) important. Take-away pointers:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Translate technical understanding of vulnerabilities to <strong>monetary terms</strong> or how well it can <strong>impact business in monetary terms</strong> and being able to leverage protection mechanisms against the same.</p></li>
<li><p>The first pointer will lead to effectively gain an insight of <strong>cost of vulnerabilities</strong> to the owner of the business and hence the <em>chief security officer</em> be able to develop a fair plan to chart <strong>measurements for <em>return on investments</em> (ROI)</strong>.</p></li>
<li><p>Being able to provide an accurate budget set-up on security and able to understand it&rsquo;s <em>return on investment</em>, the <strong>protection mechanisms placed</strong> can be more hardened and pre-planned with <em>Red Team exercies</em>.  Assign <strong> <em>appropiate</em> resources</strong> to pro-actively <strong>manage information security risks</strong>.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>All of the aforementioned three-pointers play a vital role in an industry to access it&rsquo;s security risks. Now, that we are talking about economics - the question remains how such assessments could be made easy and how <del>narrower</del> can be the road to this achievement?</p>

<p>Answer is it <strong>takes years of expertise and understanding impact</strong> by not fueling the <strong>easy way out to vulnerabilities</strong>. I have had that taste of <strong>bug bounty programs</strong> which are mostly never meant to close the <strong>monetary impact</strong> of a particular vulnerability but instead <strong> <em>focus on the softer technical side</em> </strong> and close out the <strong> <em>bugs</em> </strong>. Again, these are <em>bugs</em> and not <em>security threats as a whole</em>. Rare could be such occasions where <em>a valuable monetary vulnerability</em> has been reported. Here&rsquo;s a <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/bughunteruniversity/behind-the-scenes/charts">VRP chart from Google</a>.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="https://sites.google.com/site/bughunteruniversity/_/rsrc/1422631746620/behind-the-scenes/charts/trafficdist.png">https://sites.google.com/site/bughunteruniversity/_/rsrc/1422631746620/behind-the-scenes/charts/trafficdist.png</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>&hellip;  and that doesn&rsquo;t really <em>motivate</em> me.</p>

<p>Here are some quick pointers/gotcha&rsquo;s from this chart alone:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Monetary to <del>security researchers</del> (now that they claim to be!) for hasteful reports <a href="https://www.bbhq.net/forums/topic/3/adobe-what-a-joke"><strong>just to gain rewards</strong></a> is a plain dis-respect to self-respect but could be professionally a no-harm&#8217;er. But tl;dr <em>the bug bounty program</em> cannot itself expect more and hence is <a href="http://thehackernews.com/2013/10/Yahoo-bug-bounty-program-reward-vulnerability.html"><em>always gentle</em></a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Realizing a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/notes/facebook-bug-bounty/bug-bounty-highlights-and-updates/818902394790655">percent of valid reports</a> are made and ofcourse <strong>awarded</strong> does not verify the fact that it <em>had</em> <a href="http://shubh.am/the-deterioration-of-unmanaged-bug-bounties/">any monetary impact on the business</a>. Relaity check more vulnerabilities are dependent on each other and hence <em>often times</em> <strong> <em><u>a chain of vulnerabilities</u></em> </strong> which has to exist the same time as of depecndency of existence of others lead to a <strong>critical threat</strong>. Ofcourse, this too has a narrow window with <del>security researchers</del>.</p></li>
<li><p>It&rsquo;s real that <a href="https://www.offensive-security.com/offsec/bug-bounty-program-insights/">Perspective is everything</a> but let&rsquo;s just say sometimes a persistent <em>hackerhat</em> cowboy either way does what they had always wanted to do and <a href="https://www.exploit-db.com/papers/15823/">it&rsquo;s not yet secure-proof</a> but let&rsquo;s just <a href="https://www.offensive-security.com/backtrack/offsec-web-server-hacked/">stay strong</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>&hellip; <a href="https://medium.com/@Anonymous_India/the-truth-about-nakul-mohan-7e9c84d733c9">Really</a>?</p></li>
</ol>


<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s27.postimg.org/yctiz01nn/reallyohmy.png">http://s27.postimg.org/yctiz01nn/reallyohmy.png</a>&#8221;></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s an epic legend for a <del>security researcher</del>!</p>

<ul>
<li>What one <strong>should had gotten away</strong> with pointer above is this:</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://s21.postimg.org/j9agzia53/youget.png">http://s21.postimg.org/j9agzia53/youget.png</a>&#8221;></p>

<ul>
<li><p>&hellip; and what <a href="http://www.ubercomp.com/posts/2014-01-16_facebook_remote_code_execution"><strong><u>an accurate security research looks like</u></strong></a> had quarter more the price economy as of the previous. I highly doubt this is the best management of crowdsourced vulnerabilities and if not - very dissapointed overall.</p></li>
<li><p>&hellip; and to add <em>Managed Bug Crowd</em> isn&rsquo;t really <a href="https://engineering.linkedin.com/security/our-private-bug-bounty-program-reducing-vulnerabilities-leveraging-expert-crowds"><strong> <em>private</em> </strong></a> as claimed. It&rsquo;s doorway to <em>private accessess</em> lies in keys to the kingdom of already <em>open public</em> bug bounty managed crowd sourcing and whosoever chooses to <em>obtain a minimum criteria</em> to access the private zone is able to get it - <strong>no matter how they reach there</strong> but sometimes there are <a href="http://homakov.blogspot.in/2014/02/how-i-hacked-github-again.html">people who do what they do</a>.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2><em>problem with economics of security</em></h2>

<p>There&rsquo;s just another side of evaluating security risks and that could be the darker side. Security risk evaluation in terms of economics isn&rsquo;t well defined, complete or has any standardization but there does exists methodologies and practices such as ..</p>

<ol>
<li>NIST</li>
<li>OWASP</li>
<li>WASC</li>
<li>etc ..</li>
</ol>


<p>To cut short, <strong>there isn&rsquo;t any magic equation to be precisely accurate</strong> about security since <strong>quantity does not equal to quality</strong> and where there is <em>quality</em>, it isn&rsquo;t necessary the <em>risk is accessed by the brighter side</em>. What this means is if organizations haven&rsquo;t yet taken the appropriate measures to access it&rsquo;s security risks and quantify vulnerabilities in terms of:</p>

<ol>
<li>monetary lossess</li>
<li>reputational losses</li>
<li>asset informational lossess</li>
</ol>


<p>.. it&rsquo;s an end game at the end of the day - the darker side already might have the data one is trying to protect. Hence working to <strong> <em>solve the security equation proactively</em> </strong> might just be the wisest decision a CIO could ever made.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s solution to this existing problem and whilst escalation could be <em>internally managed and solved</em>, it isn&rsquo;t always the only way and it&rsquo;s necessary to understand why. Let&rsquo;s solve this in the upcoming posts to come-by and stay tuned folks. One liner take-away!</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Vulnerability Research and it&rsquo;s Quantification in terms of monetary impact is an essential art in itself to providing better in terms of Application Security.</p><footer><strong>Shritam Bhowmick</strong> <cite>His Information Security Diaries.</cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
