<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Events | Pwntoken - Digital Security Research]]></title>
  <link href="http://pwntoken.github.io/blog/categories/events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pwntoken.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-22T02:42:26+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://pwntoken.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Shritam Bhowmick]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://pwntoken.github.io/initial-post-and-an-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-12T01:54:25+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://pwntoken.github.io/initial-post-and-an-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Readers,</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I was in a move to port my old blog at pwntoken.wordpress.com to Octopress. I chose octopress over wordpress because of the functionality,the learning experience for the new age hackers and the speed. Along with the added repository at github, I have stood acoss on this one to be available to the public from github site publishing service.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a couple of pointers I would like to add on this introductory posts and what this blog would essentially be about:</p>

<ul>
<li>computer science</li>
<li>information security research</li>
<li>web application security research</li>
<li>network infrastructure security research</li>
</ul>


<p>A couple of other posts could make it out here. To get an overall abstract of the posts, it&rsquo;s recommended to take a note of the category section and then click on the link of your subject interest. The sole purpose of this blog is to serve personal research tracking, however, this same information could be freely used for essentially incorporating working knowledge repository given original credits are included. I hope the readers will find this blog informative and updated from time to time. I look forward to constant feedbacks, if any.</p>

<p>Regards,
Shritam Bhowmick,
Independent Security Consultant</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
